<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<configuration>
	<placeholders>
		<placeholder id="template_name">Salesforce to Database Account Broadcast</placeholder>
	</placeholders>
	<sections>
		<section id="use_case">
As a Salesforce admin I want to synchronize Accounts from Salesforce to Database.

This template serves as a foundation for setting an online sync of Accounts from one Salesforce instance to database. Every time there is new Account or a change in an already existing one, the integration will poll for changes in Salesforce source instance and it will be responsible for updating the Account on the target database table.

Requirements have been set not only to be used as examples, but also to establish a starting point to adapt your integration to your requirements.

As implemented, this template leverages the Mule batch module and [Outbound messaging](https://www.salesforce.com/us/developer/docs/api/Content/sforce_api_om_outboundmessaging.htm)
The batch job is divided into Process and On Complete stages.
The integration is triggered by a scheduler defined in the flow that is going to trigger the application, querying newest Salesforce updates/creations matching a filter criteria and executing the batch job.
During the Process stage, each Salesforce Account is filtered depending on if it has an existing matching account in the database
The last step of the Process stage groups the Accounts and inserts or updates them in database.
Finally during the On Complete stage the Template logs output statistics data into the console.

The integration could be also triggered by HTTP inbound connector defined in the flow that is going to trigger the application and executing the batch job with received message from Salesforce source instance.
Outbound messaging in Salesforce allows you to specify that changes to fields within Salesforce can cause messages with field values to be sent to designated external servers.
Outbound messaging is part of the workflow rule functionality in Salesforce. Workflow rules watch for specific kinds of field changes and trigger automatic Salesforce actions. In this case sending accounts as an outbound message to Mule HTTP Listener,
which further process this message and create Accounts in a database.
		</section>
		<section id="considerations">

To make this template run, there are certain preconditions that must be considered. All of them deal with the preparations in both source (Salesforce) and destination (Database) systems, that must be made for the template to run smoothly. 
**Failing to do so could lead to unexpected behavior of the template.**

This template illustrates the broadcast use case between Salesforce and a Database, thus it requires a Database instance to work.
The template comes packaged with a SQL script to create the Database table that it uses. It is the user responsability to use that script to create the table in an available schema and change the configuration accordingly. The SQL script file can be found in account.sql in src/main/resources/

		</section>
		<section id="run_it">

See below.

		</section>
		<section id="running_on_studio">

Once you have imported your template into Anypoint Studio you need to follow these steps to run it:

+ Locate the properties file `mule.dev.properties`, in src/main/resources
+ Fill out all the properties required as per the examples in the section [Properties to be configured](#propertiestobeconfigured)
+ Add dependency for your Database driver to the pom.xml or simply add external jar to the build path and rebuild project
+ Configure GenericDatabaseConnector in Global Elements section of the config flow to use your database specific driver. Classpath to the driver needs to be supplied here.
+ By default this template relies on existing table **"Account"** in the database of your choice, so it will perform sql statements against this table, but feel free to customize prepared statements to use different database table or columns.
+ Once that is done, right click on you template project folder 
+ Hover you mouse over `"Run as"`
+ Click on  `"Mule Application"`

		</section>
		<section id="running_on_cloudhub">

While [creating your application on CloudHub](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Hello+World+on+CloudHub) (Or you can do it later as a next step), you need to go to Deployment &gt; Advanced to set all environment variables detailed in **Properties to be configured** as well as the **mule.env**. 
Follow other steps defined [here](#runonpremise) and once your app is all set and started, there is no need to do anything else. Every time a Account is created or modified, it will be automatically synchronised to supplied database table.

Once your app is all set and started and switched for outbound messaging processing, you will need to define Salesforce outbound messaging and a simple workflow rule. [This article will show you how to accomplish this](https://www.salesforce.com/us/developer/docs/api/Content/sforce_api_om_outboundmessaging_setting_up.htm)
The most important setting here is the `Endpoint URL` which needs to point to your application running on Cloudbhub, eg. `http://yourapp.cloudhub.io:80`. Additionaly, try to add just few fields to the `Fields to Send` to keep it simple for begin.
Once this all is done every time when you will make a change on Account in source Salesforce org. This account will be sent as a SOAP message to the Http endpoint of running application in Cloudhub.

		</section>
		<section id="application_configuration">
		
**Application Configuration**

+ http.port `9090`
+ page.size `200`
+ scheduler.frequency `10000`
+ scheduler.startDelay `100`
+ watermark.default.expression `YESTERDAY`
+ trigger.policy `push` | `poll`

**Database Connector Configuration**

+ db.host `localhost`
+ db.port `3306`
+ db.user `user-name1`
+ db.password `user-password1`
+ db.databasename `dbname1`

If it is required to connect to a different Database there should be provided the jar for the library and changed the value of that field in the connector.

**Salesforce Connector Configuration**

+ sfdc.a.username `joan.baez@orgb`
+ sfdc.a.password `JoanBaez456`
+ sfdc.a.securityToken `ces56arl7apQs56XTddf34X`

		</section>
		<section id="api_calls">
		
Salesforce imposes limits on the number of API Calls that can be made. Therefore calculating this amount may be an important factor to consider. Account Broadcast Template calls to the API can be calculated using the formula:

***1 + X + X / 200***

Being ***X*** the number of Accounts to be synchronized on each run. 

The division by ***200*** is because, by default, Accounts are gathered in groups of 200 for each Upsert API Call in the commit step. Also consider that this calls are executed repeatedly every polling cycle.	

For instance if 10 records are fetched from origin instance, then 12 api calls will be made (1 + 10 + 1).

		</section>
		<section id="default_business_logic_xml">
		
Functional aspect of the template is implemented on this XML, directed by a batch job that will be responsible for creations/updates. The several message processors constitute four high level actions that fully implement the logic of this template:

1. During the Input stage the Template queries Salesforce for all the existing Accounts that match the filtering criteria.
2. During the Process stage, each Salesforce Account is checked by name against the Database, if it has an existing matching objects in database.
3. The choice routing element decides whether to perform update operation on selected database columns or to perform insert operation
4. Finally during the On Complete stage the Template logs output statistics data into the console.

		</section>
		<section id="default_endpoints_xml">
		
		
This file is conformed by three Flows.

The first one we'll call it **push** flow. This one contains an HTTP endpoint that will be listening for Saleforce's outbound messages. Each of them will be processed and thus update/create Accounts, and then executing the batch job process.

The second one we'll call it **scheduler** flow. This one contains the Scheduler endpoint that will periodically trigger **sfdcQuery** flow and then executing the batch job process.

The third one we'll call it **sfdcQuery** flow. This one contains watermarking logic that will be querying Salesforce for updated/created Accounts that meet the defined criteria in the query since the last polling. The last invocation timestamp is stored by using Objectstore Component and updated after each Salesforce query.

The property **trigger.policy** is the one in charge of defining from which endpoint the Template will receive the data. When the push policy is selected, the http inbound connector is used for Salesforce's outbound messaging and polling mechanism is ignored. The property can only assume one of two values `push` or `poll` any other value will result in the Template ignoring all messages.


		</section>
	</sections>
</configuration>